What is machine learning? In this video we
will try to define what it is and also try
什么是机器学习？本视频中将设法定义什么是机器学习，并
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
to give you a sense of when you want to
use machine learning. Even among machine
设法告诉你机器学习应该在什么情况下使用。即使在
learning practitioners there isn't a well
accepted definition of what is and what
机器学习从业者中，也没有对机器学习的统一定义。
isn't machine learning. But let me show
you a couple of examples of the ways that
但下面我将告诉你们一些现有的对机器学习的定义。
people have tried to define it. Here's the
definition of what is machine learning
下面是Arthur Samuel提出的关于机器学习做什么的定义。
does to Arthur Samuel. He defined machine
learning as the field of study that gives
他定义机器学习是一个学习领域，并在没有明确训练的情况下，
computers the ability to learn without being
explicitly programmed. Samuel's claim to
教给计算机学习的能力。追溯到1950's，
fame was that back in the 1950's, he wrote
a checkers playing program. And the
Samuel成名的原因是他编写了跳棋游戏程序。
amazing thing about this checkers playing
program, was that Arthur Samuel himself,
并且这个跳棋游戏程序的令人惊讶之处是Arthur Samuel自己并不是一个玩跳棋高手。
wasn't a very good checkers player. But
what he did was, he had to program for it to play
但他所做的是编程使计算机与自己
10's of 1000's of games against itself.
And by watching what sorts of board
玩10次’1000次。通过观察哪些布局会赢，
positions tended to lead to wins, and what
sort of board positions tended to lead to
哪些布局会输。
losses. The checkers playing program
learns over time what are good board
一段时间后，跳棋游戏程序就学到了什么是好的布局，
positions and what are bad board
positions. And eventually learn to play
什么是不好的布局。最终，就学会了玩跳棋，
checkers better than Arthur Samuel himself
was able to. This was a remarkable result.
比Arthur Samuel玩得更好。这是一个引人注目的结果。
Although Samuel himself turned out not to be a
very good checkers player. But because the
虽然，Samuel自己并不是一个好的跳棋玩者，但
computer has the patience to play tens
of thousands of games itself. No
计算机有耐心与自己玩成百上千次。
human, has the patience to play that many
games. By doing this the computer was able
没有一个人有这种耐心玩这么多次游戏。因此，计算机能获得
to get so much checkers-playing experience that it eventually became a
如此丰富的跳棋游戏经验，最终成为了一个
better checkers player than Arthur Samuel
himself. This is somewhat informal
比Arthur Samuel更好的跳棋玩者。这是有点不正式的定义，
definition, and an older one. Here's a
slightly more recent definition by Tom
也是较老的一个定义。下面是一个稍近时间的定义，由Tom Mitchell定义，
Mitchell, who's a friend out of Carnegie
Mellon. So Tom defines machine learning by
他是在卡内基梅陇大学的一个朋友。Tom是这样定义机器学习的，
saying that, a well posed learning problem
is defined as follows. He says, a computer
一个良好的学习问题定义如下：
program is said to learn from experience
E, with respect to some task T, and some
计算机程序从经验E中学习任务T，
performance measure P, if its
performance on T as measured by P improves
并用度量P来衡量性能。条件是它由P定义的关于T的性能随着经验E而提高。
with experience E. I actually think he came
up with this definition just to make it
我确实认为他如此提出定义只是想使它更押韵。
rhyme. For the checkers playing
example the experience e, will be the
对于跳棋游戏，经验E就是
experience of having the program play 10's
of 1000's of games against itself. The
计算机与自己玩10次，1000次的跳棋；
task t, will be the task of playing
checkers. And the performance measure p,
任务T就是玩跳棋的任务；性能度量P就是
will be the probability that it
wins the next game of checkers against
与新对手玩跳棋时赢的概率。
some new opponent. Throughout these
videos, besides me trying to teach you
本视频中，除了由我教你们学习外，
study, I will occasionally ask you a
question to make sure you understand the
我将偶尔问你们一个问题以确保你们已经理解内容了。
content. Here's one, on top is a
definition of machine learning by Tom
Mitchell. Let's say your email program
watches which emails you do or do not flag
假设你的邮件程序观察哪封邮件你将标为垃圾邮件，哪封将不标。
as spam. So in an email client like this
you might click this spam button to report
因此在邮件客户端，你可能点击垃圾邮件按钮标记这一些邮件为垃圾邮件，
some email as spam, but not other emails
and. Based on which emails you mark as
另外一些不是。基于此，
spam, so your e-mail program learns better
how to filter spam e-mail. What is the
你的邮件程序更好地学习如何过滤垃圾邮件。
task T in this setting? In a few seconds,
the video will pause. And when it does so,
在这个例子中，任务T是什么？接下来的几秒，视频会暂停，
you can use your mouse to select one of
these four radio buttons to let, to let me
你们可以用鼠标来选择四个按键中的一个告诉我
know which of these four you think is the
right answer to this question. That might
你认为四个中的哪个是正确答案。
be a performance measure P. And so, our
task performance on the task our system's
它可能是性能度量P。因此，我们的系统关于任务T的性能，
performance on the task T, on the
performance measure P will improve after
随着经验E而提高的性能度量P。
the experience E. In this class I hope to
teach you about various different types of
本课程中，我希望教给你们各种各样不同类型的学习算法。
learning algorithms. There are several
different types of learning algorithms.
目前也有各种不同类型的学习算法。
The main two types are what we call
supervised learning and unsupervised
主要有两类：监督学习和非监督学习。
learning. I'll define what these terms
mean more in the next couple videos. But
在下个视频中，我将定义这些名词的含义。
it turns out that in supervised learning,
the idea is that we're going to teach the
监督学习，就是我们教计算机如何做事情，
computer how to do something, whereas in
unsupervised learning we're going let
然而，在非监督学习中，我们将让计算机自己学习。
it learn by itself. Don't worry if these
two terms don't make sense yet, in the
不要担心这两个词没有意义，
next two videos I'm going to say exactly
what these two types of learning are. You
在下个视频中，我将准确说明这两类学习是什么。
will also hear other buzz terms such as
reinforcement learning and recommender
你也会听到其它的名词，如增强学习和推荐系统。
systems. These are other types of machine
learning algorithms that we'll talk about
这些是其它类型的机器学习算法，我们将会在以后讨论。
later but the two most used types of
learning algorithms are probably
但是最常使用的两类算法是
supervised learning and unsupervised
learning and I'll define them in the next
监督学习和非监督学习。我将在下两个视频中定义，
two videos and we'll spend most of this
class talking about these two types of
并且我们会用大部分的课时来讨论这两类学习算法。
learning algorithms. It turns out one of
the other things we'll spend a lot of time
另外，我们将会花大量时间说明
on in this class is practical advice for
applying learning algorithms. This is
应用学习算法时的实际建议。
something that I feel pretty strongly
about, and it's actually something that I
这也是我觉得很有用的，也是据我所知
don't know of any other university
teaches. Teaching about learning
其它大学未教的。教授学习算法
algorithms is like giving you a set of
tools, and equally important or more
就像给你一组工具，但和给你工具同样重要的或者说更重要的是
important to giving you the tools is to
teach you how to apply these tools. I like
教你如何使用这些工具。
to make an analogy to learning to become a
carpenter. Imagine that someone is
我喜欢用学习成为一个木匠做比喻。想象一下，某人
teaching you how to be a carpenter and
they say here's a hammer, here's a
在教你如何成为一个木匠，并且他说这是一个榔头，这是一个
screwdriver, here's a saw, good luck.
Well, that's no good, right? You, you, you
螺丝刀，这是一个锯子。好运气，可是，事实上并不好。
have all these tools, but the more
important thing, is to learn how to use
你有了所有的工具，但更重要的是要学习如何正确地使用这些工具。
these tools properly. There's a huge
difference between, between people that
对知道如何使用机器学习算法的人，
know how to use these machines learning
algorithms, versus people who don't know
与不知道如何使用机器学习的比较，将有很大的不同。
how to use these tools well. Here in
Silicon Valley where I live, when I go
在硅谷，当我
visit different companies even at the
top Silicon Valley companies very often I see
参观不同的公司，即使是在那些我看到
people are trying to apply machine
learning algorithms to some problem and
他们设法在一些问题上应用机器学习算法的公司，
sometimes they have been going at it for
six months. But sometimes when I look at
有时他们已经在问题上做了6个月。
what they're doing I, I, I say, you know,
I could have told them like, gee, I could
当我看到他们在做时，我会说，你知道，我真希望我在
have told you six months ago that you
should be taking a learning algorithm and
六个月前就告诉你们，你们应该使用学习算法，
applying it in like the slightly modified
way and your chance of success would have
并且小小修改一下，成功率就会高很多。
been much higher. So what we're going to
do in this class is actually spend a lot
因此，本课程中要做的就是花大量的时间讨论
of time talking about how, if you actually
tried to develop a machine learning
假设你确实设法开发机器学习系统，
system, how to make those best practices
type decisions about the way in which you
那么对于你建立你的系统的方式，如何作出那些最佳的实际类型决策，
build your system so that when you're
applying learning algorithm you're less
以致于当你应用学习算法时，你不大可能
likely to end up one of those people who
end up pursuing some path for six months
像那些在做了六个月后放弃的人一样，就此结束放弃。
that, you know, someone else could have
figured out it just wasn't gonna work at
其它人可能已经明白它根本不值得做，
all and it's just a waste of time for six
months. So I'm actually going to spend a
它只是浪费了六个月的时间。因此，我将花费大量的时间
lot of the time teaching you those sorts
of best practices in machine learning and
来教你们机器学习和AI中那些最好的实践经验，
AI and how to get this stuff to work and
how we do it, how the best people do it in
以及如何使这项任务工作，我们如何来做，硅谷和世界上最优秀的人是如何做的。
Silicon Valley and around the world. I
hope to make you one of the best people in
我希望使你们成为
knowing how to design and build serious
machine learning and AI systems. So,
在知道如何设计和建立各种各样的机器学习及AI系统方面最好的人。
that's machine learning and these are the
main topics I hope to teach. In the next
因此，机器学习以及如上提到的是我最希望教的。
video, I'm going to define what is
supervised learning and after that, what
下一个视频，我将定义什么是监督学习，之后介绍什么是非监督学习。
is unsupervised learning. And also, start
to talk about when you would use each of them.
并且，开始讨论你可以在什么时候使用它们。